I bring a report.
Details about the man who
recently entered your service,
Don Orts, have come to light.
He seems to be quite cleverly hiding it,
but he—along with his parents—are
employees of the First Prince.
He's well-established there, then.
The households of nobles,
especially royalty,
are managed quite strictly
on various fronts.
In the interest of preserving
confidentiality,
there are often strict limits
on who employees can interact with.
In many cases, they marry other employees
per their master's recommendation.
And children born to such marriages
also swear their loyalty to the master.
I believe that the First Prince
sent him here as a spy.
Probably.
Don't tell anyone what you've discovered.
Now that we know he's a spy,
we can use him.
Of course.
The insight to recognize him as
a spy during a first impression...
Your Highness never ceases to amaze me.
I'm not sure I'd call it insight.
Even after I agreed to
let him work for me,
Name: Minister-Prince of Justice Noah Ararat
Sex: Male
Level: 3 / ∞
HP: E+F
Fire: F+B
MP: F+F
Water: E+S
Strength: E+E
Wind: F
Stamina: F+F
Earth: F
Intelligence: F+E
Light: F
Spirit: F+F
Dark: F
Speed: F+F
Dexterity: F+F
my stats didn't increase.
That made it obvious.
Also, someone from the Bardsley store
has requested an audience with you.
They say they have found the
treasure you were seeking.
Right.
I guess that 10,000-rean
bait I gave him paid off.
Ah, if it isn't the Wise Prince!
I pray this day finds you well.
A good preface.
What have you found?
Ah, of course.
I do hope it pleases Your Highness.
A painting?
That is correct.
A painting known as Huwawa.
It is the work of a renowned artist,
but it is, of course,
no ordinary painting.
Is it cursed?
Most impressive, Your Highness!
Behold.
This is a replica made around the
same time Huwawa was painted.
A replica?
I can see it.
It looks like the same
girl in both, but...
A cursed painting that matures?
Precisely.
Through Leviathan, I can
tell that the original
is giving off a strange aura.
In which case...
Y-Your Highness?!
What?!
Wh-What is this?!
Born Blessed, So I'll Obtain Ultimate Power
Uh-huh. Uh-huh. I see.
Huh? Y-You can understand
what she's saying?
Yes. She says this piece was
painted with her blood.
Its painter killed her while
she was still a child
and mixed her blood into the paint.
I had no idea...
"I want to repay you for freeing me," eh?
In that case...
swear loyalty to me.
I understand.
I-Incredible...
I never thought a cursed painting
could turn into this...
So cutting her bonds with Leviathan
made it possible for her to enter
and leave her vessel at will?
My earth magic gained a slight plus.
Name: Minister-Prince of Justice Noah Ararat
Sex: Male
Level: 3 / ∞
HP: E+F
Fire: F+B
MP: F+F
Water: E+S
Strength: E+E
Wind: F
Stamina: F+F
Earth: F+F
Intelligence: F+E
Light: F
Spirit: F+F
Dark: F
Speed: F+F
That means she'll probably
be useful in the future.
Episode 9
The Highest Trust
Well, give it a try, Huwawa.
Huh?!
I-Is... that... m-me?!
She says she can do more, too.
Like this?
Try touching her.
What?!
My left hand can touch her, but
the right hand passes through!
She can make it work for both,
but this is only a test.
I-Incredible... For someone I only
met today to replicate me so well...
Well, the physical form is thanks
to her link with my armor ring,
but I think this can definitely
be called transformation magic.
Well done. As thanks, I'll
pay any price you name.
Contact me if you find anything else.
I will!
Byron Alan
Merchant
What brings you here today?
And what is that behind you?
Ada has been honored with
His Majesty's favor
and officially accepted
as one of his attendants.
This is merely a humble
token of my gratitude.
Oh?
Ada is the girl Byron sent
to the palace as a servant.
So the servant he chose six
years ago, per my advice,
has risen to the level of attendant.
I see. You really splurged, didn't you?
That's worth about 30,000 rean.
What's the matter?
Oh, nothing... I'm just surprised
you guessed the amount.
Brilliant as always!
At any rate, that's good news.
So she starts as an attendant?
Yes. I'm hoping she'll achieve
the status of wife eventually.
Indeed.
Consorts are divided into four ranks.
Attendant
First are attendants, then concubines,
Concubine
and above them are wives.
Wife
And standing above all of them as the
emperor's legal wife is the empress.
Empress
They rise in the ranks based on
how much the emperor favors them
and how high their sons rank.
Noah's mother reached the rank of wife
when the emperor granted
Noah his "Wise" title.
Thirteenth Prince
Wise Prince
It goes without saying that
there's only one empress.
So if you're aiming for the top, the
rank of wife is as high as she can go.
Right.
All I can do now is pray that she earns
more and more of the emperor's favor.
No, it's all politics from here.
Of course, earning the emperor's favor
is the fastest way to get there,
but outside of that, what's important
is the politics among the consorts.
Is that so?
For example...
what if someone were to switch Ada's
perfume with a scent the emperor dislikes?
Based solely on how
cutthroat consorts can be,
the inner palace is even more of a den
of demons than the world men live in.
I... I see!
Send her money.
Now that you know it's all politics,
you know what you must do, right?
Yes, of course! Thank you so much!
Zoey.
Yes, Master?
Take this letter to my mother
along with 10,000 rean.
U-Um... wouldn't Dylan be a more
suitable messenger to the palace?
Men are forbidden to enter the
inner palace where my mother is.
That's why I only see
her around once a year.
Princes are taken from their
mothers soon after they're born.
Only once... a year?
And please give my mother
a message for me.
Of course. What shall I tell her?
"I consider myself Ada's guardian."
Y-You mean to use your
mother for politics?
That's right.
But... she's your mother...
That's how the imperial family works.
Even between parent and child, profit
and status take priority over emotion.
If Ada rises in the ranks,
she could be a good ally to my mother.
What a... fascinating
world you live in...
Understood. I will go at once.
By the way...
Yes?
How is your mother doing?
She is forever grateful that you
gave her a home in the capital
and even gave her a job.
But...
Oh, nothing. She said she might have
imagined it, so it isn't worth mentioning.
It isn't nothing. Tell me.
A-All right...
Part of my mother's job is to open and
close the gate every morning and night.
Yesterday, she heard a sound at night,
so she went to investigate...
I-Is someone there?
She was unable to see them clearly,
but she suspects there may be someone
sneaking in and out at night.
I see. You were right to inform me.
For now, tell your mother to say
nothing of this to anyone else.
Wha? Th-Then you think she imagined it?
We'll soon find out.
Today just wasn't your day.
You're lucky to be alive.
Y-You mean someone... was
trying to kill my mother?
Yes.
He must have thought she saw him leaving
the mansion and tried to silence her.
Well done, Huwawa.
Amazing... She was just
my mother a moment ago...
Zoey.
Y-Yes?
Return to Dosso with your mother's
"body" for the time being.
Her hometown would be
the place to bury her.
Um...
It'll only look that way, of course.
If she stays here,
she'll be targeted again.
I'll send for you when this is all over.
Take some time off until
then, just the two of you.
Master...
Thank you so much! Thank you so much!
U-Um, but, Master... should we
really let that man get away?
Yes. I have Huwawa monitoring him.
Huh?!
You truly are amazing, Master!
Where am I?
So you're awake.
Take it easy. You nearly died.
I... did?
You don't remember?
After reporting that you'd
killed the woman who saw you,
you were stabbed by a go-between.
In other words, you failed
in your role as a spy,
so you were cast out.
I had been monitoring you
because I expected this,
but I'm surprised you really did it.
I see.
And people are supposed
to be treasures...
You foresaw everything,
right down to my being cast out.
You are indeed the
Wise Prince they say you are.
I am in awe of your keen insight.
If I had been employed by you from
the start, and not as a spy...
It's not too late.
You're saying that if things
had worked out differently,
you would be working for me now, right?
If so, it's not too late.
Are you serious?
But in return, I will punish betrayal
even more harshly than they did.
Once you've sworn loyalty to me,
your life is mine.
But...
I also won't cast you out.
Th-Thank you so much.
Please allow me to work for you.
My wind stat gained a +F.
Name: Minister-Prince of Justice Noah Ararat
Sex: Male
Level: 3 / ∞
HP: E+F
Fire: F+B
MP: F+F
Water: E+S
Strength: E+E
Wind: F+F
Stamina: F+F
Earth: F+F
Intelligence: F+E
Light: F
Spirit: F+F
Dark: F
Speed: F+F
Dexterity: F+F
Luck: F+F
That proves he's genuinely
sworn his loyalty to me.
Water
Wind
Earth
In that case, focus solely on recovering.
And we'll need to give you
a new name and status.
I'll make you the adopted
son of a ruined noble.
I'll find a place in Almeria where
you can serve as a local governor.
Stay there until things settle down.
Thank you so much... for everything!
U-Um...
I don't know if this will even
slightly repay my debt to you,
but there is one thing I must tell you.
Speak.
My former master, First Prince
Gilbert, gave the emperor a gift.
What?!
Noah, what is this urgent matter?
What has you in such a panic?
I will say it now.
Please stop drinking the Wine of Poinix.
Poinix...
You mean the wine produced
in Gilbert's fief
that he began offering
to the palace this year?
Yes.
Why?
It is a fine wine that can act as a
tonic with continued consumption,
but if taken with a certain food,
it becomes a terrible poison.
Oh? And what is that certain food?
The food known as Dragon's Claw.
The one that the crown prince
and I eat once a year
in a ritual honoring our ancestors?
Yes. It has been nearly a
year since you received the wine.
By drinking it regularly
with the crown prince,
you've basically proven that
it contains no poison.
So when the time comes, no one will
suspect the Dragon's Claw's role in it.
Even if anyone considers it,
it'll be seen as an accident.
Which gives the murderer a perfect alibi.
Yes.
You're certain about this?
A death-row criminal was offered
both items and told that he'd be freed
if he consumed both and survived.
The result was immediate.
So if Crown Prince Albert and I
carry out the ritual as usual,
you're saying that both of us will die?
Precisely.
Well done, Noah. Impressive.
You've done well to expose this plot.
Cruz. Summon Henry.
Send soldiers to the First Prince's
mansion and launch an investigation.
At once.
Noah, you may take your leave.
I will contact you about your reward.
Yes, sire.
That night, the force that marched
on the First Prince's mansion...
found proof through a butler's
testimony that experiments
were being conducted to test poisons
on illegally traded slaves.
Gilbert's plan to seize the empire after
killing the emperor and crown prince
was stopped by Prince Noah's counsel
before it could be carried out.
Why does something feel wrong?
The emperor seemed to have eyes
and ears everywhere until now.
That was shown to me over and over again.
So why didn't he know what
was going on this time?
Unless...
You are truly clever indeed, Noah.
Y-You already knew, then?
Yes.
In fact, I have not been drinking
the Wine of Poinix at all.
I have been emperor too long.
I'm sure there are those
who can wait no longer.
But you do not seem to be one of them.
Correct.
I see.
Noah Ararat,
I hereby appoint you vice
minister of military affairs.
You will serve concurrently
as minister of law.
I also name you governor-general
of the first army,
also known as the imperial guard.
Yes, sire.
What is this? What does this mean?
I do not intend to go
down without a fight.
If my own son kills me, I'll be
a laughingstock for generations.
But if that does happen...
I want you to seize the capital
with the imperial guard
and choose a suitable replacement.
He wants me... to choose the right
person to be the next emperor?!
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Control:
Becky Cottrill
Edgar Cruz
Gabriella Alabanza
S Bilyeu
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Control:
Becky Cottrill
Edgar Cruz
Gabriella Alabanza
S Bilyeu